MELVYN THOMAS WILLIAM LING

MELVYN.LING@GMAIL.COM | 289 788 2149 | HAMILTON, ONTARIO L8L 2L6 LINKEDIN.CA/MELVYN-LING | GITHUB.COM/MELVYNLING | MELVYNLING.GITHUB.IO/PORTFOLIO

SUMMARY

A front-end web developer whose creative flair and adaptive nature strike the balance between form and function. As a recent graduate of the University of Toronto's School of Continuing Studies Web Development program, a strong command of HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, and Node.js amongst other techs and frameworks has been established. He uses his diverse experience, spanning political science, customer service, the trades, and recent freelance experience to optimise and contextualise his projects to best serve their target demographics. His passions include learning, beating personal bests, functional design, and all things JavaScript.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- HTML/CSS
- JavaScript
- jQuery

- Node.is
- React.js
- Handlebars.js
- MERN Stack
- API/AJAX
- Google Firebase
- Version Control (GitHub)
- MySQL/MongoDB
- Heroku

PROJECTS

cryptoTRKR Lead Developer

github.com/MelvynLing/cryptoTRKR | cryptotrkr.herokuapp.com

• This app allows the user to see the historical data of their favourite 4 cryptocurrencies. It is a serverless Reactapp that stores the user's selection in their browser's localStorage. It also utilizes React Context API to make the API calls to the CryptoCompare API.

Technology used: CSS, HTML, JavaScript, NodeJS, Lodash, MomentsJS, highchartsJS, CryptoCompare API, React, localStorage

BitCoin Value Tracker Team Developer

github.com/MelvynLing/bitCoinValueTracker gentle-spire-69297.herokuapp.com

• This application allows the users to see the historical trends of Bitcoin. The user enters entry and exit dates for potential bitcoin investments and is shown how profitable they could have been. I was responsible for the API call, the math and logic involved with calculating the rates, as well as the overall appearance of the application.

Techs used: HTML, CSS, jQuery, JavaScript, NodeJS, MomentsJS, handlebarsJS, coindesk API, Materialize UI, MySQL

Train Scheduler Lead Developer

github.com/MelvynLing/trainscheduler melvynling.github.io/trainscheduler

• This app allows the user to create a train schedule, allowing them to see their trains arrival and departure times. This is a serverless application - utilizing google Firebase to store the user's inputs instead of a standard database.

Techs used: CSS, HTML, JavaScript, jQuery, Firebase, Bootstrap,

West Ham United App Lead Developer

github.com/MelvynLing/whuapp westhamapp.herokuapp.com/

• This is an app that allows the owner to show a sports team's recent schedule, as well as their most current roster, as well as take in inputs for a promotion. The owner can then log in and add/edit players to the roster and add/edit games to the schedule. Google Firebase was used for the database in this application

Techs used: CSS, HTML, JavaScript, Firebase, React, Material UI, d3

EXPERIENCE

Customer Service Representative

May 2016 – December 2018

OSG Canada Inc.

Burlington, ON

- Responsible for answering technical questions regarding products, customer service duties, order entry, quoting
 specialized tools, daily sales reporting, daily purchasing, customs paperwork, as well as receiving and preparing of
 tools for coating.
- Assisted in the coordination of the first tool dispensing system at a local customer, where users would input their requested tools and receive them. Tracked and maintained inventory to ensure the smooth operation of dispensing system.

Operations Assistant

(Intermittently) April 2012 – Present

Alco Sheet Metal Ltd.

Hamilton, ON

- Supported managers, tradespeople, and all others in the daily operations of the company, assisting with data entry and I.T. related activities, as well as in the tool shop and on various jobsites on an as needed basis.
- Facilitated training for two colleagues on new computer programs and operating systems, advised in the selection of programs for managers.

Automobile Claims Adjuster/Disposition Adjuster

Sept 2014 - Oct 2015

Aviva Canada Inc

Hamilton, ON

- Worked as a front-line agent, set up automobile insurance claims for customers who had been involved in an automobile accident via phone or email.
- Selected to take part in a third-party report team, to investigate potential automobile claims with customers who has been reported to be in an accident.

EDUCATION

School of Continuing Studies, Full-Stack Web Development Bootcamp.

December 2018

- Toronto, Ontario

University of Toronto

Bachelor of Arts (Honours), Political Science.

April 2012

- Hamilton, Ontario

McMaster University